<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="com.soartech.soar.ide.feature"
      label="Soar IDE"
      version="1.1.0"
      provider-name="Soar Technology, Inc.">

   <description url="http://soaride.googlecode.com">
      Soar IDE
   </description>

   <copyright>
      2009 Soar Technology, Inc. All rights reserved.
   </copyright>

   <license url="http://www.soartech.com/download/soardev/SoarIDE_Academic_License.txt">
      Important!
Do not download, use, copy, transmit, distribute, or install
the source, object, or executable code or any related documentation
associated with this software unless you have read, fully understand,
and agree to be bound by the following Master License Agreement
and Schedule.
By downloading, using, copying, transmitting, distributing or
installing the source, object, or executable code or any related
documentation for the software (the &quot;Licensed Product&quot;), you
agree to all of the terms of this agreement (&quot;Agreement&quot;).
SOAR TECHNOLOGY, INC.
MASTER LICENSE AGREEMENT
Soar Technology, Inc. (“SoarTech”)
3600 Green Court, Suite 600
Ann Arbor, MI  48105
Tel:  (734) 327-8000
Fax: (734) 913-8537
This License Agreement (this “Agreement”) is by and between SoarTech
and the individual or organization (“Customer”) downloading,
using, copying, transmitting, distributing, or installing the
software, and is made effective as of the date of download, copying,
transmission, distribution, or installation, whichever is sooner
(the “Effective Date”).  The specific software and types of license
(e.g., Evaluation License, Proof of Concept License, Partner
License, Developer’s License, Research License, Production License,
or End User License Agreement) licensed under this Agreement
will be set forth in one or more agreed Schedules.  For good
and valuable consideration, the receipt and sufficiency of which
are hereby acknowledged, the parties agree as follows:  
1.  License.
(a) Subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, SoarTech
grants Customer the limited right to use, in object code form
only, the software described on the applicable Schedule (“Software”)
and any operating instructions delivered with the Software (“Documentation”).
The Software and Documentation and any and all copies or modifications
thereto are referred to collectively as the “Licensed Product”.
Customer agrees to pay SoarTech the license fee in accordance
with the terms set forth in the applicable Schedule. 
(b) The licenses granted herein shall be nonexclusive. 
(c) Except as set forth in the attached schedule, the licenses
granted herein shall be non-transferable except in the event
that the Customer is acquired or merges with another entity.
In the event of a merger or acquisition, all license terms and
schedules are transferred and remain in effect.
2.  Limitations on License.
EXCEPT AS SET FORTH IN THE ATTACHED SCHEDULE
(a) The Licensed Product shall be used only by Customer for Customer’s
sole and exclusive benefit and shall not be used to provide time-sharing
or other similar services unless terms and conditions for such
services are expressly stated on the applicable Schedule.  
(b) Customer shall not reverse engineer, decompile, modify or
change any portion of the Software or attempt to do any of the
foregoing.  
(c) Customer shall not transfer, distribute, or sublicense the
Licensed Product to others, and Customer’s license shall automatically
terminate in the event of such a transfer or distribution.
(d) The license in this Agreement is subject to any additional
rights, restrictions and conditions set forth in the applicable
schedule. 
3.  Term.  The license term will begin on the Effective Date
of the applicable Schedule and will expire at the end of the
term specified on the applicable Schedule. Either party may terminate
this Agreement if the other party materially breaches any of
the terms and conditions of this Agreement and such breach is
not cured after ten (10) days written notice.  In addition, any
party may terminate this Agreement for convenience.  Upon termination
or expiration of this Agreement for any reason, Customer shall
promptly return the Licensed Product to SoarTech, or destroy
all copies of the Licensed Product, at SoarTech’s sole option.
Sections [9, 12, 13, 14, and 15] of this Agreement shall survive
termination or expiration of Customer’s license and this Agreement.
4.  Payment.  
(a) For acquisitions of this Licensed Product by or for the U.S.
Federal Government, all payments shall be made in accordance
with the Prompt Payment Act (Title 31 U.S.C. Chapter 39).
(b) For all acquisitions not applicable to section 4(a), all
payments under this Agreement, shall be made in United States
dollars, and if not paid when within net 30 days, or in accordance
with terms agreed upon in the attached Schedule, will be subject
to interest at the rate of eighteen percent (18%) annually, or
the maximum amount allowed by applicable law if lower, calculated
from the date when payment becomes overdue until payment is received.
Customer agrees to pay all federal, state, local and other taxes
based on this Agreement, the Licensed Product or its use or for
any related services, excluding taxes based on SoarTech’s net
income. 
5. Federal Acquisitions of Commercial Software.  If indicated
on the applicable Schedule, the Licensed Product qualifies as
“Commercial” computer software within the meaning of the acquisition
regulation(s) applicable to this procurement  For acquisitions
of this Software by or for the U.S. Federal Government, or by
any prime contractor or subcontractor (at any tier) under any
contract, grant, cooperative agreement or other activity with
the U.S. Federal Government, by accepting delivery of this Software,
the Customer herby agrees that this software qualifies as “Commercial”
computer software within the meaning of the acquisition regulation(s)
applicable to this procurement.  The terms and conditions of
this License shall pertain to the government’s use and disclosure
of this Software, and shall supersede any conflicting contractual
terms or conditions.  If this License fails to meet the government’s
needs or is inconsistent in any respect with Federal law, the
Customer agrees to return this Software, unused, to SoarTech.
6.  Professional Services
(a) SoarTech shall provide the implementation, training, project
management, programming and other services (if any) set forth
in the applicable Schedule (the “Professional Services”).  
(b) Customer agrees to pay SoarTech for Professional Services
in accordance with the terms set forth in the applicable Schedule.
(c) Customer shall provide SoarTech with timely access to information,
personnel, facilities, supplies, computers, passwords, and other
items reasonably requested by SoarTech in connection with the
performance of the terms specified in the applicable Schedule.
Any delay resulting from Customer’s failure to provide any such
items, or any delay resulting from Customer’s failure to provide
timely decisions and approvals, shall correspondingly extend
any schedule that may be specified in the applicable Schedule.
(d) Either party may request a change to the Professional Services
set forth in the applicable Schedule by submitting a written
statement describing in detail the requested change and the reasons
for the change (“Change Request”).  After receipt of the Change
Request, the parties shall discuss the availability of personnel,
equipment, resources, and facilities necessary to fulfill such
Change Request and the resulting adjustments to the applicable
Schedule (including changes to fees and schedules).  SoarTech’s
time spent evaluating a Change Request may result in additional
billable hours.  No change to the applicable Schedule shall be
effective unless both parties have agreed in writing to a modified
Schedule.
(e) Customer shall reimburse SoarTech for all reasonable out-of-pocket
expenses incurred by SoarTech in connection with the Professional
Services, including but not limited to travel, living, meals,
long distance telephone and mailing expenses.  
7.  Maintenance Services.
Only Maintenance Services listed in the Schedule will be provided
with this license and Customer agrees to pay the fee set forth
in the applicable Schedule for maintenance services.  Such services
are subject to the following Terms and Conditions:
(a) SoarTech will provide telephone support for the Software
on regular working days between 9:00 a.m. and 4:00 p.m., Eastern
Time.  SoarTech’s assistance will consist of providing general
advice on the installation, operation and use of the Software
and assistance with suspected problems with the Software.  
(b) For all reported problems, SoarTech will work to determine
the source of the problem.  SoarTech will attempt to correct
all documented problems reported to SoarTech by Customer that
SoarTech is able to recreate at SoarTech’s site, and will deliver
any bug fixes to Customer.  SoarTech may identify errors as arising
from non-SoarTech hardware or software, or from unauthorized
modifications to SoarTech Products.  In such a case, SoarTech
reserves the right to charge Customer for correcting such errors
per the billing charge on the applicable schedule.  In the event
that no billing charges are indicated on the applicable Schedule,
SoarTech reserves the right to charge Customer for correcting
such errors per SoarTech’s then-current hourly rates for Maintenance
Services provided.
(c) SoarTech will provide new releases and/or upgrades to Software
for no additional charge to Customers under the Maintenance Services
contract and Customer will implement them as soon as is reasonably
practical.  SoarTech will have no responsibility to provide Maintenance
Services for any versions of the Software other than the current
and immediately prior version.  Releases and/or upgrades do not
include new products which provide significant new features and
functions not provided in the current product line, which port
existing Software to new hardware or software platforms, which
provide significant new functionality on new hardware or software
platforms, or which SoarTech designates with a new product number.
(d) Before contacting SoarTech with a question, Customer shall
take reasonable steps to resolve the question.  For example,
Customer shall recreate and verify the alleged problem and review
the Documentation before contacting SoarTech.  
(e) Customer shall perform tasks as reasonably requested by SoarTech
to aid in the resolution of problems, and shall implement all
reasonable workarounds to problems as directed by SoarTech. 
Upon request of SoarTech as necessary to resolve a Customer problem,
Customer will provide SoarTech with a copy of requested Customer
data in the machine-readable format reasonably requested by SoarTech.
Customer shall be responsible for maintaining adequate back-ups
of all data used in connection with the Software.  
(f) If Customer terminates Maintenance Services and subsequently
wishes to reinstate maintenance service on any Software, it must
immediately upgrade to the most recent release of Software, at
their expense.  SoarTech will not be obligated to provide Maintenance
Services in the event that the License Agreement is terminated
or Customer does not pay the License Fee, Maintenance Fees, or
any other amount due to SoarTech.  
8.  Limited Warranty.  
(a) If agreed by the parties in the applicable Schedule, SoarTech
will warrant that the Licensed Product will perform substantially
in accordance with the accompanying specifications for a period
of one year from the Effective Date as indicated in the attached
Schedule.  SoarTech agrees to repair or replace defective Licensed
Product, provided the defect is discovered within a reasonable
period of time after acceptance.   Any liability of SoarTech
will be limited exclusively to refund of the price, if any, Customer
paid to SoarTech for the particular copy of the Software.  Under
no circumstances will SoarTech or any of its principals, shareholders,
officers, employees, affiliates, contractors, subsidiaries, or
parent organizations, be liable for any indirect, incidental,
consequential, or punitive damages whatsoever relating to the
use of the Software, even if SoarTech has notice of the possibility
of such damages.  
(b) EXCEPT FOR THE WARRANTY SET FORTH IN THE PRECEDING PARAGRAPH,
THE SOFTWARE, AND ALL ACCOMPANYING FILES, DATA AND MATERIALS,
ARE DISTRIBUTED AND PROVIDED “AS IS” AND WITH NO WARRANTIES OF
ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED.  The Software is provided
with all faults, and the entire risk as to satisfactory quality,
performance, accuracy, and effort is with the user.  Further,
there is no warranty against interference with the Customer’s
enjoyment of the Software or against infringement.  Without limiting
the foregoing, SoarTech makes no warranty that the Software is
free of viruses.  Customer acknowledges that reasonably prudent
procedure requires that any means of data processing, including
the Software, be thoroughly tested with non-critical data before
you rely on it, and Customer assumes the entire risk of using
the Software.  
9.  Proprietary Rights. 
(a) All rights to and in the Licensed Product – including, but
not limited to, copyright, patent, trademark and trade secret
rights—belong to SoarTech and/or its licensors, and SoarTech
holds title to each copy of the Licensed Product.  SoarTech reserves
all rights to the Licensed Product not specifically granted herein.
(b) Customer agrees to reproduce all copyright and other notices
in each copy of the Software made by Customer.  
(c) All customizations, enhancements, modifications and new code
delivered to Customer pursuant to this Agreement shall be deemed
“Software” and hereunder and shall be owned by SoarTech.  
10.  Public Relations/Marketing.  SoarTech may elect to use Customer’s
name in Public Relations, Marketing, or required reports to U.S.
Government agencies.  Additionally, SoarTech may elect to use
Customer’s name in refereed conference publications stemming
from U.S. Government Funded efforts to research or develop the
Licensed Product.  Customer may elect to use SoarTech’s name
in required reports to U.S. Government agencies.  Additionally,
Customer may elect to use SoarTech’s name in refereed conference
publications stemming from research involving the Licensed Product.
Customer agrees to notify SoarTech prior to such use.  SoarTech
will be provided with a review and editing opportunity at least
one week (five business days) prior to anticipated submission
deadline.  All requests to SoarTech should be submitted to “Attention:
Soar Technology Contracts” to the SoarTech address or fax number
indicated in the header of this document.
11.  Security; Inspection.  Certain Software may be designed
to be used and accessed over a browser via either the Internet
or a Customer Intranet.  In connection with such Software, Customer
agrees to use industry-standard security measures to minimize
the risk of unauthorized access to and use of such Software.
Upon the request of SoarTech from time to time, but not more
than one time per year, Customer will certify to SoarTech in
writing the extent of its use of the Software and distribution
to employees, as well as the security measures it has implemented
in connection with the Software.  In addition, for Production
Licenses only, Customer grants to SoarTech, or a SoarTech agent,
the right to inspect Customer’s computer operations and Customer’s
system reports upon reasonable notice and not more than one time
per year to determine if Customer is in compliance with all the
terms and conditions of this Agreement. SoarTech agrees that
it shall act reasonably in the exercise of this right and shall
cooperate with Customer to avoid disruption of Customer’s computer
operations and to preserve the confidentiality of any of Customer’s
files.  
12.  Indemnification.  Customer agrees to indemnify, defend,
and hold harmless SoarTech, its principals, shareholders, officers,
employees, affiliates, contractors, subsidiaries, and parent
organizations against all losses of any kind (including reasonable
attorney fees) in connection with any suit, action, or claim
arising out of your use, downloading, copying, transmittal, distribution,
or installation of the Software.
13.  Limitation of Liability.  Customer alone shall be responsible
for: (a) the accuracy and adequacy of information and data furnished
for processing; and (b) any use made by Customer of the output
of the Software or any reliance thereon.  Customer shall also
be responsible for the continued operation and maintenance of
the computer equipment and third-party software used with the
Software, and shall comply with all operational, environmental
and maintenance recommendations and requirements of the applicable
licensors, vendors and manufacturers.  CUSTOMER AGREES THAT ANY
LIABILITY OF SOARTECH, REGARDING THE LICENSED PRODUCT OR THE
SERVICES IN QUESTION RELATING TO THIS AGREEMENT AND THE LICENSED
PRODUCT, SHALL BE LIMITED TO THE AMOUNT OF LICENSE FEES ACTUALLY
RECEIVED BY SOARTECH FROM CUSTOMER UNDER THIS AGREEMENT.  IN
NO EVENT SHALL SOARTECH BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL,
INDIRECT, COVER, CONSEQUENTIAL, EXEMPLARY OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES;
ANY DAMAGES BASED ON INJURY TO PERSON OR PROPERTY; OR ANY LOST
SALES, PROFITS OR DATA, EVEN IF SOARTECH IS TOLD THAT ANY OF
SUCH DAMAGES MAY OCCUR.  THE SOFTWARE IS NOT DESIGNED OR LICENSED
FOR USE IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS SUCH AS OPERATION OF NUCLEAR
FACILITIES, AIRCRAFT NAVIGATION OR CONTROL, OR LIFE-CRITICAL
APPLICATIONS.  SOARTECH, TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED UNDER
APPLICABLE LAW, EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ANY LIABILITY RESULTING FROM
USE OF THE SOFTWARE IN ANY SUCH HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS AND ACCEPTS
NO LIABILITY IN RESPECT OF ANY ACTIONS OR CLAIMS BASED ON THE
USE OF THE SOFTWARE IN ANY SUCH HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS.  FOR
PURPOSES OF THIS PARAGRAPH, THE TERM “LIFE-CRITICAL APPLICATION”
MEANS AN APPLICATION IN WHICH THE FUNCTIONING OR MALFUNCTIONING
OF THE SOFTWARE MAY RESULT DIRECTLY OR INDIRECTLY IN PHYSICAL
INJURY OR LOSS OF HUMAN LIFE. 
14.  Confidentiality.  All information and data delivered or
disclosed by a party to the other party pursuant to this Agreement,
including but not limited to SoarTech’s Licensed Product, SoarTech’s
License fee, SoarTech’s Professional Services and/or Maintenance
fees (the “Information”), is the proprietary and confidential
information of the disclosing party.  Each party agrees to protect
the Information and not to distribute or allow access to the
Information to any other party without the prior written consent
of the disclosing party.  The obligations in this paragraph shall
not apply to data or information which: (a) is generally available
to the public through no breach of this or any other confidentiality
obligation, or (b) was lawfully in the possession of the receiving
party prior to the receipt of such data or information from the
disclosing party.  In addition, either party may disclose information
of the other party as required by law or court order; in such
event, such party shall use its best efforts to inform the other
party prior to any such required disclosure.  Notwithstanding
the above, Customer and SoarTech may disclose information to
U.S. Government employees on a need to know basis.  
15.  Miscellaneous.  
(a) The Licensed Product shall not be exported or re-exported
by Customer in violation of any export provisions of the United
States or any or applicable jurisdiction.  
(b) This Agreement constitutes the entire, final and exclusive
Agreement between the parties and supersedes any and all other
prior or contemporaneous oral or written representations or agreements
between the parties relating to the subject matter hereof.  No
amendments or modifications of this Agreement may be made except
in writing, signed by both parties.  
(c) Neither Customer nor SoarTech shall have the right to assign
this Agreement or any of its related obligations hereunder. 
(d) The failure by any party to exercise any right provided herein
shall not be deemed a waiver or forfeiture of any such right.
(e) For acquisitions of the Licensed Product by or for the U.S.
Federal Government, this Agreement is governed by the U.S. Code
and the Contract Disputes Act of 1978.
(f) Except for acquisitions of the Licensed Product by or for
the U.S. Federal Government, this Agreement is governed by the
laws of the State of Michigan, without regard to its choice of
law provisions.  The parties each consent to jurisdiction and
sole venue in a state or federal court in Washtenaw County, Michigan.
(g) Each party shall be excused from performance and shall not
be liable for any delay caused by the occurrence of any contingency
beyond the reasonable control either of the excused party or
its subcontractors or suppliers.  These contingencies include,
but are not limited to, war, sabotage, insurrection, riot or
other act of civil disobedience, labor disturbance or shortage,
act of public enemy, failure or delay in transportation, act
of any government affecting the terms hereof, accident, fire,
explosion, flood, severe weather or other act of God.  
(h) This Agreement does not designate either party as the agent,
employee, legal representative, partner or joint venturer of
the other party for any purpose whatsoever.  
SOAR TECHNOLOGY, INC.
SCHEDULE A
ACADEMIC LICENSE AND SERVICES
This Schedule incorporates the Master License Agreement between
Soar Technology, Inc. (“SoarTech”) and “Customer”.
Software License:
Name/Version/Application:   SOAR IDE
Term of License:  Perpetual, Academic
Fee:  0 U.S.D.
Maintenance Services:  No Maintenance Services are Provided
Professional Services:  No Professional Services are Provided
Professional Services:  No Training Services are Provided
Warranties:  THE LICENSED PRODUCT, AND ALL ACCOMPANYING FILES,
DATA AND MATERIALS, ARE DISTRIBUTED AND PROVIDED “AS IS” AND
WITH NO WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED.
Commercial Software Designation:  The Licensed Product is “Non-Commercial”
Computer Software
Additional Payment Terms:  None
Additional License Restrictions and Terms:
1. Customer agrees that the license in this Schedule is solely
for academic purposes, and that the Customer has no right under
this Schedule or License Agreement to use, transfer, or sell
the Licensed Product, Derivative Works, or Professional Services
that utilize the Licensed Product to any third party.
2. Number of Installations Permitted:  1 Installation (Seat)
   </license>

   <url>
      <update label="Soar IDE Update Site" url="http://soaride.googlecode.com/svn/update/"/>
   </url>

   <requires>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.runtime"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.debug.core"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.ide"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.resources"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.console"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jface.text"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.editors"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.workbench.texteditor"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.views"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.debug.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.search"/>
   </requires>

   <plugin
         id="com.soartech.soar.ide"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.soartech.soar.ide.ui"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.soartech.soar.ide.help"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

</feature>
